Name: Peter Jacobs

Email: thisispeterj@gmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/peterjweb/ Contact Number: (408) 610-0117

# Summary:

QA Engineer with 8 years of experience in manual testing and a strong understanding of the software development life cycle. Adept at creating and executing test cases and identifying and reporting defects using various tools. Committed to collaborating with both developers and business teams to resolve defects and improve software functionality and usability.

### Skills:

- Test Case Design and Execution
- Manual and Automation Testing
- Defect Tracking and Reporting
- Agile Development

### Tools and Software:

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nightwatch.js, SQL, Git
- Jira, GitHub, Jenkins, iTerm, Postico, Postman, SoapUI, Chrome Developer Tools, Slack, Asana

## Work Experience:

Senior QA Engineer at EKA Solutions Inc. (2017-2022)

- Held weekly QA team meetings to analyze business requirements and create comprehensive test cases
- Conducted manual and automated functional testing through all stages of development
- Implemented and tested various integration types and APIs using Postman
- Verified database testing using tools such Postico along with SQL
- Tracked and reported defects using Jira, assigning priorities as needed

Client Support and QA Engineer at ImageShack (2013-2016)

- Designed and executed manual test cases for both web and mobile platforms
- Created and maintained a custom Zendesk help support system

### **Education:**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Video Imaging, Cogswell Polytechnical College, (2003-2005)